A Finding Aid to the Robert Smithson and Nancy Holt Papers, 1905-1987, bulk 1952-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.smitrobe
Archives of American Art
- Printed Material, 1955-1985; Series 8; 5.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-11, Box 18, RD 31
  - Books (Box 7)
    - Handbook of the Collections: Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - If I had a Mind ??? (Ich Stelle Mir Vor), by Klaus Groh, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Metro 14, ed. by Alfieri, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Report on the Art and Technology Program of the Los Angeles Museum of Art 1967-1971, by Maurice Tuchman (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Robert Smithson: Sculpture, ed. by Robert Hobbs, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Transference: Roget's Thesaurus, by Vito Acconci, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Writings of Robert Smithson, ed. by Nancy Holt, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Booklet, "Pamphlet of Essays Occasioned by an Exhibition of Painting at the Guggenheim Museum,", 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Booklet, "Reclamation Works,", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Booklet, "Whitney Review,", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, circa 1955-1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1965-1969; 5 Folders (Box 8, Folder 2-6)
  - Clippings, 1970-1974; 5 Folders (Box 8, Folder 7-11)
  - Clippings, 1975-1979; 5 Folders (Box 8, Folder 12-16)
  - Clippings, 1980-1985; 3 Folders (Box 8, Folder 17-19)
  - Clippings, by Robert Smithson, 1963-1973 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Event Announcements, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Event Announcements, Hayden Planetarium, "Domain of the Great Bear,", circa 1955- 1966; 3 Folders (Box 8, Folder 22-24)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1959-1966; 4 Folders (Box 8, Folder 25-28)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1967-1968; 5 Folders (Box 8, Folder 29-33)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1969; 5 Folders (Box 8, Folder 34-38)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1969; 5 Folders (Box 9, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1969-1970; 2 Folders (Box 9, Folder 6-7)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1970; 3 Folders (Box 9, Folder 8-10)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1971; 5 Folders (Box 9, Folder 11-15)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F5
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1972; 4 Folders (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1973-1979; 5 Folders (Box 10, Folder 5-9)
    Oversized material housed in RD 31
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1980-1985; 6 Folders (Box 10, Folder 10-15)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Non-Smithson Related, 1965-1980 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Newsletter, Public News + News Network, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Periodicals, with Articles by Robert Smithson (Box 10)
    - 0 to 9, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Artforum, 1967; 1982 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Art Now: New York, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Art Present, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Arts Yearbook, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Aspen, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Oversized material housed in Box 18, F6
    - Avalanche, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Harvard Advocate, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Kalejdoskop, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - On Site, 1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Pan, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ta,', 1967-1968 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals, with Articles on Robert Smithson (Box 11)
    - Art in America, 1976-1985; 4 Folders (Box 11, Folder 8-11)
    - Artforum, 1970-1981; 2 Folders (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
    - Arts, 1981; 1984 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Arts Canada, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Interfunktionen, 1970-1971 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Substitute, 1972 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Taide, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Printed Material, Miscellaneous, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Inventory List of Unfilmed Books and Periodicals, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Inventory List of Unfilmed Phonograph (Music) Records, circa 1970s (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Exhibition Catalog, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Oversized material from Box 9, F13
  - Periodicals, Aspen and Avalanche, 1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Oversized materials from Box 11, F1-F2
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1974-1975 (Box RD 31)
    Oversized materials from Box 10, F6 and F16
- Scrapbook, 1966-1973; Series 9; 0.3 Linear feet Box 11, Box 16
  The scrapbook contains clippings of Smithson's published articles from 1966 to 1973 with annotated shorthand notes on album pages.
  The scrapbook retains its original arrangement.
  - "Robert Smithson 1938-1973, Essays, Articles, Statements,", 1966-1973 (Box 16)
- Artwork, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 10; 4 Folders Box 11
  Artwork consists of Christmas cards collaged by Smithson, and sketches by Smithson and Leo Valledor.
  The series is arranged by artwork type.
  - Artwork by Robert Smithson (Box 11)
    - Christmas Card, "Christmas is for Children,", circa 1963 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Christmas Card, "Santa Claus vs. the Creature from the Black Lagoon,", circa 1963 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Sketches, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Sketches by Leo Valledor, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Photographs, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 11; 5 Folders Box 11, Box 18
  Photographic materials include prints and negatives of Smithson with friends, promotional Hollywood movie stills, copyprints of other artists' artwork, and original photographs of artwork by Rosemarie Castoro, Michael Heizer, and N.E. Thing Co.
  The series is arranged by subject.
  - Robert Smithson with Friends, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 27)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F7
  - Robert Smithson with Howard Junker, New Jersey, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Promotional Movie Stills, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Works by Other Artists, Original Prints, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Works by Other Artists, Copy Prints, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Robert Smithson with Friends, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Oversized material from Box 11, F27
- Artifacts, circa 1950s-1970s; Series 12; 0.5 Linear feet Box 11, Box 14, OV 19
  Artifacts consist of a paper bag silkscreened with a Campbell's soup can (Warhol), promotional buttons (N.E. Thing Co.), various organic materials, and two art kits. The Geometric Units for Logic Test kit consists of 17 geometric shape cutouts; the Gravity for Traveling I kit consists of over 15 samples of mixed materials, including foams, glass, fabrics, plastics, and metals.
  The series is arranged by artifact type.
  - Bag, Campbell's Soup Can (Andy Warhol screenprint), circa 1960s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 32)
    Oversized material housed in OV 19
  - Buttons, N.E. Thing Co., "Artoficial,", 1967 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Geometric Units for Logic Test, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Gravity for Traveling I, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Framed Moths, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Rattlesnake Head, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 14)
  - Organic Material, Unidentified Amphibious Organism, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 14)
  - Bag, Campbell's Soup Can (Andy Warhol screenprint), circa 1960s-1970s (Box OV 19)
    Oversized material from Box 11, F32
- Nancy Holt Papers, circa 1960s-1980s; Series 13; 1.7 Linear feet Box 12-13, Box 15, OV 27
  The Nancy Holt papers consist of correspondence, a grant application, printed materials, and project files and audio visual material related to her motion picture films Pine Barrens (1975) and Suntunnels (1975).
  The series has been arranged by material type.
  - Correspondence, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Grant Application, National Endowment for the Arts, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, Exhibition Reviews, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Event Announcements, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Oversized material housed in OV 27
  - Project, Pine Barrens, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 12 and Box 15
  - Project, Pine Barrens Abstract, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Project, Pine Barrens Film Log, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Project, Suntunnels, circa 1970s (Box 13, Folder 8)
    Oversized material housed in Box 15
  - Project, Suntunnels Clipping, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Drawing of Ann Tobin, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Pine Barrens (workprint), 1975; 14 film reels in 5 film cans (Box 12)
    Oversized material from Box 13, F5
  - Pine Barrens (trims), 1975; 1 Film reels (Box 12)
  - Pine Barrens (soundtrack), 1975; 1 sound tape reel: 10.5 in (Box 12)
  - Pine Barrens (release print), 1975; 3 duplicate videocassettes: 1 digital betacam, 2 VHS (Box 15)
  - Pine Barrens (outtakes), 1975; 3 duplicate videocassettes: 1 digital betacam, 2 VHS (Box 15)
  - Suntunnels (release print), 1975; 3 duplicate videocassettes: 1 digital betacam, 2 VHS (Box 15)
    Oversized material from Box 13, F8
  - Event Announcements, 1974 (Box OV 27)
    Oversized material from Box 13, F4